《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
GAETA: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
你会用你的双臂拥抱我
You're gonna hold me in your arms,
你会说你爱我
you're gonna tell me that you love me.
你疯了
You're insane.
你杀了我  我下载到新的躯壳  我回来  我们从新开始
You kill me, I download. I come back, we start over.
我不属于这里  让我出去!
I don't belong here! Let me out!
有些人加入了赛昂人的警察部门
Some of those guys who joined up with the Cylon police,
你知道他们是不可理喻的
I bet they're in over their heads, you know?
如果有一天  这一切都结束了
One day, when this is all over,
类似盖塔这样的人都会被绞死
guys like that are gonna get strung up.
而像你我这样的人  则是负责
Guys like you and me,
将绳子打结的人  把绳子绑得紧紧的
we're gonna be there, tying the knots, making them tight.
你从哪里得到的这玩意?  谁是你的情报源?
Where are you getting this stuff? Who's your source?
我不知道  消息源没有透露他们的名字
I have no idea. The source won't tell me what their name is.
也许这样对大家更安全
It's probably safer for all of us.
总统先生?
Mr. President?
早上好  盖塔
Good morning, Gaeta.
这是一份死刑判决书  你看过这个名单上的人名吗?
This is a death warrant. Have you seen the names on this list?
你知道他们会有什么反应吗?
Do you have any idea what they're about to do out there?
我从"死亡投递点"那里拿到这个
I got this from the dead drop,
是从管理部门的线人那里得来的
from the source in the administration.
这是张死亡名单  而凯莉的名字就在上面
It's a death list and Cally's name is on it.
走 别向后看
Run, don't look back. Go!
掩护
Take cover!
我们在汇合点遭到埋伏
SAM: We were ambushed at the rendezvous.
赛昂人确切知道我们所在的位置
The Cylons knew exactly where we were gonna be.
那并不能说明艾伦...         我什么也没干
That doesn't mean Ellen... I didn't do anything!
这是那张我画给你的地图
This is the map that I drew for you.
你本应该烧掉的  但你妻子说帮你去烧
You were gonna burn it, but then your wife offered to do it for you.
你知道自己该做什么的
You know what has to be done here.
为了她好  还是由你来做
Now, it would be better for her sake if it was you.
快点  跟上!
Come on! Move! Move, move!
从整个设施中撤退
Evacuate the entire facility.
你也应该和我们一起走  盖尤斯  我们也给你留了个位置
You should go as well, Gaius. There's a place for you, too.
快走
CONNOR: Walk.
以下指控的证据已上报给特别法庭
Evidence for the following charges have been presented to the Circle,
你和敌人狼狈为奸
that you carried arms for the enemy,
你实施的多起搜捕行动都是针对人类的
that you carried out multiple raids against the human population,
在其中一起搜捕过程中 有23人被你和你的人杀害
and that during one raid, 23 people were killed by you and your men
就是在你们侵犯阿尔提米斯神庙的时候
during the assault on the Temple of Artemis.
那不是事实
It's not true!
这些是被你所杀的人的名单
These are the names of the people killed by you and those under your command.
你看看这些名单!
You look at those names!
康纳
SEELIX: Connor.
特别法庭核查了证据 认定你有叛国罪
The Circle has examined the evidence and found you guilty of treason
与反人类罪
and crimes against humanity.
在判决前  你还有什么要说的吗?
Do you have anything to say before sentence is passed?
我只是想帮助他们
I was trying to help people.
你干的活可不是一个好活  对吧?
You didn't do a very good job then, did you?
就让我们结束吧
All right, let's just get this over with.
我帮助过他们  我帮助过好多人啊
I helped people. I helped lots of people!
军士长...军士长!军士长  我帮过凯莉  我救了凯莉
Chief? Chief? Chief, I helped Cally. I saved Cally.
我救了凯莉
I saved Cally!
"你救了凯莉"是什么意思??
What do you mean, you helped Cally?
是我...是我...是我救的她
I'm the one. I'm the one who did...
是我在他们射击前让她跑的
I'm the one who let her go when they were gonna shoot her.
我让她离开车队  我说:"现在快跑  拼命跑  离开这里"
I took her out of line. I said, "Go, run right now, get out of here. "
她做到了  她跑开了
And she did. She ran and she got away.
是我  军士长  我救的凯莉
Because of me, Chief. I helped Cally. I saved Cally.
凯莉确实是跑开了
Cally did get away somehow.
他们在那次神庙搜捕中杀害了23人!
Well, they killed 23 people during the Temple raids,
12个男人  8个女人  和3个孩子
12 men, eight women and three children.
还有孩子!
Children!
我的儿子就在这名单里!
My son is on this list!
他的名字就在这!
His name is right there,
不知是哪个龟孙子把他加上的
and that frakking son of a bitch put him there.
那么  救了凯莉  就算是的话
So, saving Cally, if that happened,
就能弥补杀死我儿子的过错吗?
does that make up for killing my son?
回答  军士长
Answer the question, Chief.
是否救了凯莉 就能让他杀了23个人吗?
Does saving Cally let him off the hook for killing 23 others?
是你做的吗  杰米? 是你杀了这些人吗?
Did you do this, Jammer? Did you kill these people?
回答我
Answer me.
你知道那里的人都疯了  军士长
It was crazy down there, Chief.
你知道的
You know that.
你们做这个决定太仓促了
You make these decisions so fast.
当你们在追捕时 那些人站出来  举着双手
You're making an arrest, and people come out with their hands up.
但有些时候  那只是个诡计
But sometimes that's just a trick.
他们说他们投降了  但接着  他们却开枪了
They tell you they're surrendering, and then they open fire.
我们以为他们是起义军的
We thought they were insurgents.
在我们看到他们的尸体时  才知道不是
It wasn't until after, when we saw the bodies...
那我该如何做呢?
What was I supposed to do?
不  不能抵消罪过
No, it doesn't.
根据法律条文 叛国罪是判死刑
Under the Articles, the punishment for treason is death.
现在确认宣判
Sentence confirmed
并在今天执行 第二次逃亡后的第三天
and carried out on this, the third day of the Second Exodus.
军士长
Chief...
我错了!
I'm sorry!
你妈的话太多了
There's too much frakking talk.
等等!
Wait.
我错了
I'm sorry!
我儿子...
CONNOR: My son.
凯文
Kevin.
他只有7岁啊
He was only seven years old.
我们走吧
Let's go.
快点
Come on.
康纳  我们走吧
Connor, let's go.
这不是我想参加的
This isn't what I signed up for.
我看不见
GIRL: I can't see.
妈妈
Mom...
好小伙子
Good boy.
嗨 亲爱的
Hey, sweetie.
我还需要被照顾吗?
Am I on watch?
不  不  你很好
No, no, you're fine.
来  让我抱抱  过来  你过来
Here, give him to me. Come here. You come here.
到爸爸这来 嗨  小宝贝  接到你了
Come to Daddy. Oh, hey, buddy. Hey, buddy, there you go.
我知道 妈妈比我抱更舒服  对吧?
I know. Mommy's much more comfortable than me, huh?
凯莉?        嗯
Cally? Mmm-hmm?
你在那个星球的时候
When you were down on the planet,
你从卡车旁跑走
you ran away from the trucks,
是有人帮你吗?
did anybody help you?
是一个NCP警察还是别人呢? (译者注:NCP新卡布里卡警察)
One of the NCP goons or anybody?
什么?  没有
What? No.
等下  是有个
Wait. Yeah.
有人让我快跑
Somebody told me to run.
那可能是一个NCP警察吧
It probably was one of those goons.
那以后我还没想过呢
But I haven't thought about it since.
嗨  你怎么知道的呢?
Hey, how did you know about that?
我意思是  你为什么问呢?
I mean, why do you ask?
没什么 快睡吧
No reason. Go back to sleep.
好的
Okay.
在我看来  那不是他的错
In my opinion, it wasn't his fault.
我虽不愿意承认  但上将是对的
I hate to admit it, but the Admiral's right.
他是在一个极端困难的情况下
He was in an impossible situation.
如果我是他  可能我也会那样
I'd have probably done the same in his position.
那好  如果那是必须的  那这种行为也是无可厚非的
Well, if that's the way it has to be, then that's the way it has to be.
感觉不糟吗?
No hard feelings?
没有
None.
错误已经发生  不用怀疑  没有任何疑问
Mistakes were made. Of that, there's no question.
但是过去的...
But the past
已经过去了
is the past.
我想大家都会同意我们应该继续前进
I think we can all agree that we'd like to move on.
你们被愚弄了 你们太仁慈了
You fools. You're being too lenient.
他背叛了你们  他想让你们去死
He betrayed you, actively sought your deaths.
你们还觉得没关系吗?   你们还有自尊吗?
Doesn't that matter to you? Don't you have any self-respect?
别打岔了  他们听不到你的
I wouldn't bother. They can't hear you.
不要让我发火  盖尤斯
Don't make me angry, Gaius.
她发火时  你不会喜欢他的
You wouldn't like her when she's angry.
不
No.
我一直想要你
ROSLIN: I've always wanted you.
噢  不
Oh, no.
什么?
What?
我是在做梦  对吧?
I'm dreaming, aren't I?
是的  你是在梦里
Yes, you are.
嗨
Hey.
你睡过觉了吗?
Did you get any sleep?
在你死的时候睡的
Sleep when you're dead.
不错
Nice.
那东西都是些什么?
What is all that?
我找回了我储备室里面的一些东西
I got my gear out of storage.
从来都没想过还能见到它们
I never thought I'd see any of this stuff again.
嗨
Hey.
什么     过来
What? Come here.
别这样  行吗?
Just don't, okay?
打扰了  伙计
WOMAN: Excuse me, guys.
那么  总统先生
So, Mr. President,
新12殖民地法人还有多久宣誓就职?
how long before the new Quorum of Twelve can be sworn in?
3天
Three days.
我会以个人名义提名你作我的副总统
I will personally place your name in nomination as my vice president.
当他们承认你后  我会提出辞职  然后你宣誓就职
Once they confirm you, I submit my resignation and you get sworn in.
整个过程不会超过一个小时
I think it should take less than an hour.
你就这样下台  也不搏一次了?
You're stepping down without a fight.
我的意思是汤姆・查莱克可以要些东西
It means Tom Zarek wants something.
你何不亮出自己的底牌
So why don't you put your cards on the table,
让我看看  那是不是一个我愿意付的价码
and let's see if it's a price that I'm willing to pay?
我是一个现实主义者
Well, I'm a realist.
我对在这个办公室长久待下去从不抱幻想
I never had any illusions about remaining in office for very long.
并且上将显然也会认为
And the Admiral's made it quite clear
没什么会比把我扔进监狱更好了
that he'd like nothing better than to put me
如果我尽力的话
in a cell if I try to hang onto power.
他会给你一个人情的
He's trying to do you a favor.
你和我都很清楚 没有军队的支持
You and I both know how impossible it would be to govern this fleet
来管辖这个舰队是不可能的
without the backing of the military.
我同意  这是我们在此的原因
I agree. That's why we're here.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
就算这样  我还想在新政府里干点什么
Even so, I want to be included in the new government.
我不再想做一个外人  无关者
I don't want to be on the outside looking in anymore.
好吧
Okay.
你在新卡布里卡反对波塔尔
You stood up to Baltar on New Caprica.
为此你差点就丢了命
You nearly lost your life for your trouble.
这个舰队需要这种勇气
This fleet needs that kind of courage.
副总统的职位就是你的  只要你想的话  汤姆
The vice presidency is yours if you want it, Tom.
好  谢谢你
Well, thank you.
乐意之极
You're welcome.
你是开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
谁许可这家伙进作战指挥中心的?
Who gave this man permission to enter the CIC?
上将的命令  先生
Admiral's orders, sir.
通信系统在拯救行动时遭到了严重破坏
Communications took some serious hits during the rescue,
盖塔先生过来帮忙修复这些故障
and Mr. Gaeta's offered to help with repairs.
这样  很好啊
Well, isn't that nice?
一个人能够叛变  伙同敌人一起
A man can turn his coat, collaborate with the enemy,
造成了数千人的死亡
contribute to the deaths of thousands,
但是老头子就为了修电话  突然间  所有这一切都可以赦免
but the old man needs his phones fixed, and suddenly all is forgiven.
赛昂人会找到我们 我们必须利用所有能用的力量
HELO: The Cylons find us, we're gonna need every hand we've got.
等赛昂人找到我们  阿格森先生
The Cylons found us, Mr. Agathon.
你的朋友盖塔会在欢迎委员会里的
Your friend Gaeta was on the welcoming committee.
听着!看着我
Hey! Look at me!
你现在在这儿  看来可以帮帮我的忙
As long as you're here, maybe you can help me out.
在我被拘留期间  我失去了一些东西
I'm missing something. I lost it in detention.
就在你做赛昂人小乖乖的时候
Since you're so buddy-buddy with the Cylons,
可能你知道它在哪里吧?
maybe you know where it is.
如何?
How about it?
你知道我的眼睛在哪里吗?
Do you know where my eye is?
少!
ADAMA: Saul!
上将
TIGH: Admiral.
都回去工作
Back to work.
跟我走        是
Walk with me. Yeah.
在今后的两周时间里  有很多工作要做
We have a lot of work in the next couple of weeks.
我需要你睡觉休息 休息好  准备好  好吗?
I need you to get some sleep. Get rest, get ready, all right?
哦  我现在就准备好了
Oh, I'm ready right now.
我可能稍微有点过火了 但我能把握住的
I may be a little rough around the edges, but I can still hold my own.
你可以告诉那个烤面包机爱好者
And you can tell that toaster lover over there
我还是这艘船的副长!
that I'm still the XO of this ship!
我们走吧
ADAMA: Let's go.
别碰我
Get your hands off me.
你正在让你自己难堪  少
You're embarrassing yourself, Saul.
你才是那个该不好意思的
You're the one that should be embarrassed,
让一个波塔尔的党羽到处乱走
letting one of Baltar's henchmen
就像什么都没发生一样
walk around like nothing's happened.
去睡觉  马上!  这是个命令
Go sleep this off. That's an order.
噢  好吧  就去睡觉
Oh, yeah, just go to sleep,
忘了所有的 那就忘了所有发生的事情
forget about it all, just forget about everything.
但是我不会忘记的!  我不打算忘记!
Well, I'm not forgetting. I'm not gonna forget!
这个控状是在战争中为敌人
The charges are carrying arms for the enemy in a time of war,
开枪射击3名平民  并且通敌
shooting three civilians and collaboration with the enemy.
现在投票
I call the vote.
有罪
Guilty.
有罪 有罪
Guilty. Guilty.
嗯  有罪
Yeah, guilty.
有罪
Guilty.
表决意见一致  判决死刑
The vote being unanimous, the sentence is death.
查得维克在Monarch号上
Chadwick's aboard the Monarch.
我会通知我们那边的人  他会处理的
I'll contact our man there. He'll take care of it.
谁有香烟?
Has anybody got a cigarette?
还剩多少人?
TYROL: How many more of these do we got?
57人   三天了  我不敢想象这三天我们是如何过的
Fifty-seven. Three days. I can't believe that's all the time we've got.
那就不要再抱怨了
TIGH: Then stop wasting it, bitching and moaning.
在我们参加的时候  都知道这是有时限的
We all knew there was a clock when we signed on.
他们绝大多数都是有罪的  太恶劣了
Most of these fraks are so guilty, they stink.
我可以在一个小时内把50个叛完
I could get through 50 of these things in an hour.
你以为我们是一群暴徒?
You think we're a bunch of thugs
一时兴起就决定处决人吗?
handing out punishment on a whim?
杰米没有活下来 因为你认为他是有罪的
Jammer didn't get air-locked because you thought he was guilty.
有证据你看到了那个报告
There was evidence. You read the witness reports.
他想辩解  但是被这个法庭判有罪
He was tried and convicted by this Circle.
这是关系到正义的事情  你懂吗?   正义!
This is about justice. You got that? Justice!
好的  是  是
Yeah, okay. Okay.
嗨  不要让我找到错误
Hey, now don't get me wrong here.
我喜欢你  康纳  你是个好人
I like you, Connor, you're a good guy.
下一个
Next case.
菲里克斯・盖塔
SEELIX: Felix Gaeta.
指控是通敌罪 反人类罪
Charges are collaborating with the enemy and crimes against humanity.
我不想判这个   你以为我喜欢吗?
I don't want to do this! You think I like it?
我和盖塔在作战指挥中心共事了4年  像一家人
I stood beside Gaeta in the CIC for almost four years. He was like family.
但现实是他是盖尤斯的首脑官员
But the fact remains he was the Chief of Staff to Gaius Baltar,
仅这一项就够指控他了
and that alone is enough to convict him.
依我说  在这个家伙身上
And I'm saying that on this particular guy,
我们找不到任何有力的证据
we do not have any hard evidence.
我们找不到目击证人  什么也没有
We have no witnesses, nothing.
我们所知道的就是他为波塔尔工作  就这些
All we do know is that he worked for Baltar. That's it.
是的  我同意山姆的说法  我们需要详细的证据
Yeah, yeah. I've got to go with Sam on this one. We need something specific.
你要详细的?  你以为会是波塔尔出主意吗? 那家伙?
You want specific? You think Baltar ran things, that guy?
他只是个傀儡
He was the public face.
但是盖塔  他才是主脑  所有人都知道
But Gaeta, he was the brains, everyone knew that.
都是他具体操作 是他准备的文书 他批准的处决名单
He ran the operation, he did the paperwork. He approved the death lists...
那你是怎么知道的呢?  你在那儿吗?
How do you know that? Were you there?
你看到他批准让哪一个被处决了吗?
Did you see him approve one single death list?
他知道凯莉在处决名单上
He knew Cally was on the death list.
你说什么?  你怎么知道的?
What are you talking about? How do you know that?
看这里 这是执行的名单 凯莉的名字在这
Look there. That's a distribution list, and there's Cally's name.
这里有盖塔的名字
And there's Gaeta's name.
他看到了她的处决命令
He saw her execution order.
那也只是迫于形势
It's still all circumstantial.
当他看到这个名单的时候
We don't know what Gaeta did or
我们不知道盖塔做了什么和没有做什么
didn't do when he saw that list.
我同意他们的说法
Jean. I gotta go with them on this one, Sam.
不  山姆  当你看到这样一份死亡名单
No, Sam, you see a death list like that,
你知道无辜的人将会被处决
you know innocent people are gonna die,
你会不做点什么吗?  你有罪
and you do nothing about it? You're guilty.
我要求表决
I call the question.
表决菲里克斯・盖塔是否有罪已被要求
The question of the innocence or guilt of Felix Gaeta has been called.
特别法庭将表决
The Circle will vote.
我判他有罪
I vote guilty.
有罪
CONNOR: Guilty.
Guilty.
山姆?
SEELIX: Sam?
不  别烦我  我做完该做的了
No, don't bother. I'm done.
我们继续表决        我不干!
We're still voting. I'm not.
我做完了  我做完所有自己该做的了
I'm done. I'm done with this whole thing.
战争对我来说已经结束了  对不起
The war's over for me. I'm sorry.
好吧  那好吧
Okay, that's fine.
现在是四票对零票  军士长  你的判定呢?
It's still four to none, Chief. What's your vote?
不  等下  我们需要6个人表决的
No, wait a minute. We need six votes.
不  别管它         不  别管你才是!
No, screw you! No. Screw that.
我们是审判团  那是我们的规矩  我们必须要6个人表决
We're a jury, that's how it was set up! We need six votes.
我们现在不满6人  我也不干了
Without six votes, I'm out, too.
他是对的  我们需要6个人
He's right. We need a sixth.
你好吗  盖尤斯?
How are you, Gaius?
我还活着
I'm alive.
我想是还活着
I suppose that's something.
谢谢你
Thank you.
可能要打搅你一下  我有点迷糊了
You'll have to excuse me. I'm slightly confused.
我在这里待了多久了?
How long have I been here, exactly?
3天
Three days.
3天?
Three days?
你们3天后才想到我在哪?
So, it's taken you three days to remember where I was?
没人忘了你的  盖尤斯
No one's forgotten you, Gaius.
只是关于是否该让你上船
It's just there's been some controversy about
有些争论
whether or not you should have been let on board or not.
我简直不能想象还有人在质疑我的价值
I can't believe there's still a question of my value.
那肯定会是个问题的
There will always be a question.
你是一个人类
You are a human.
现在  你看
Now, look.
我帮过你
I helped you.
我把莎伦的孩子给了你
I gave you Sharon's child.
是  没错  确实是你
Yes, that's right, you did.
而且救了那孩子也给你加了分
And the child's rescue did weigh in your favor.
但是  投票也陷入了僵局
However, the vote's deadlocked.
有三个同意你应该被留下 另外三个反对
Three in favor of your being allowed to stay, and three against.
还有一个型号没有表态
With one model still undecided.
事实上  最后的决定取决于6号
The fact is the decision rests with the Sixes.
我们在准备粗略的失踪人口报告
We're starting to see a rash of missing persons reports.
嗯  我们在那个星球上留下了数千人
Well, we left thousands of people on that planet.
不  不对  有些人是确认生还的
No, this is different. These are people known to have survived,
但是有些是在逃亡后失踪的 比如说像杰米
but who have gone missing since the exodus. Jammer, for instance.
那个甲板手 昨天下午我还看到他的
Deckhand? I saw him yesterday afternoon.
是的  但他今天早上的集合就没有他
Yeah, but he didn't report at muster this morning.
卧室里没有  医务室里也没有  就像他突然消失了一样
Bed-check negative, sickbay negative, it's like he just vanished.
有多少人失踪?
How many people are missing?
今天有13人  卡拉狄加上两人.别的地方有11人
Thirteen, as of today. Two on Galactica, 11 elsewhere.
他们中所有人都是被确认过生还的
Every one of them confirmed as a survivor by multiple witnesses,
但是没了
and then, poof, gone.
有这个"失踪人口"案的新进展就告诉我
Keep me posted on any more missing persons.
我想知道怎么回事
I want to know about it.
是  长官  现在如果您允许的话
Yes, sir. Now, if you'll excuse me,
我有一个跳绳的约会
I have a date with a jump rope.
嗨  我已经减了不少了
Hey, I've dropped half a stone.
继续跳吧
Keep jumping.
嗨
Hey.
你过得如何?
How you doing?
你知道的  还好吧  你呢?
Oh, you know, I'm making do. How are you?
我不错啊  你为什么问呢?
I'm good. Why do you ask?
嗯  我听过你的情况  你被…
Well, I heard about your situation. You were...
没错
Right.
我在尝试不再想起那件事  知道吗?
I just try not to think about it anymore, you know?
有一点像你...
You know, I'm kind of like you,
坐在豪华的殖民地一号的办公室里
sitting in your cushy little office on Colonial One,
帮波塔尔干那些肮脏的事
doing all of Baltar's dirty work for him.
可能从来没有想过在我身上正发生着什么事情  对吧?
You probably never even thought about what was happening to me, right?
我不知道你的情况
I didn't know about your situation.
如果我知道的话  我会设法让你出去的
If I had, I would have tried to get you out.
嗯
Mmm.
就像我现在都说了50遍的话
And like I've just said about 50 times now,
我效力的是联邦的合法总统
I was serving the legal President of the Colonies.
我们都选了他的  记得吗?
We all elected him, remember?
那么  这就可以宽恕你吗?
Is that supposed to excuse it?
你想让我说什么?
What do you want me to say?
也许我可以做得更多
Maybe I could have done more.
但当赛昂人着陆的时候
But I thought that when the Cylons landed,
我继续工作是很重要的 可以从内部帮助大家
it was important for me to keep my job, to help from the inside.
就靠支持波塔尔 并让赛昂人压迫我们？
By propping Baltar up and letting the Cylons walk all over us?
不是的! 不是的!  我给抵抗组织传递消息
No, no. I fed information to the Resistance.
是我设立了"死亡投递点"  那是一个狗食盆
I set up dead drops. There was a dog bowl.
是我透露了赛昂人刑场的位置 通过内部备忘录
I passed along Cylon positions, internal memoranda...
万岁  菲里克斯
Right, Felix.
你真是个该死的英雄
You're a frakkin' hero.
我必须要结束对你的感情
Whatever feelings I had for you have to stop.
我的感情干扰到了我的判断
I allowed my feelings to cloud my judgment.
我保护了你
I protected you.
我给了你第二次机会
I gave your species a second chance.
我甚至反对我们的赛昂人姐妹  都为了什么?
I even turned against a sister Cylon, and for what?
我是个赛昂人  盖尤斯
I'm Cylon, Gaius.
不知为什么我都忘了自己是赛昂人
Somehow I lost sight of that.
你不仅仅是一个机器
You are much, much more than a machine.
你是一个人
You're a person.
一个真实的人
A real person.
一个女人
A woman.
并且在和我相爱
And you're in love with me.
并且这让人心痛
And it hurts.
我知道这让人心痛
I know it hurts.
但是相信我
But believe me,
我是唯一能让它好起来的人 你没看到吗?
I am the only one that can make it better, don't you see?
我是唯一的
I am the only one.
不  需要结束这一切
No. This has to end.
你需要我 你需要我!承认吧!
You need me! You need me, admit it! Admit it, you need me!
我也需要你!
And I need you, too!
你听到了吗?  我也需要你
Did you hear me? I need you, too!
也许我之前应该从那开始
Maybe I should've started with that.
这是一个审判团  我需要大家明确这一点
This is a jury. I want to make that clear.
这不是什么评分或人身评定
It's not about settling scores or personal grudges.
这是个审判团
It's a jury.
我们处理的都是人渣中的人渣
And we're just dealing with the worst of the worst.
那些比穿上NCP警服或与
People that did more than put on an NCP uniform
赛昂人地下交易做孽更多的人
or make a deal with the Cylons.
他们是杀人犯  他们才是真正的叛国者
They're the killers, the real traitors.
哦  但这一切都是非法的  对吧?
Yeah, but none of this is legal, right?
不  不  这是合法的
No, no. It's legal.
你一定是在和我开玩笑
STARBUCK: You've got to be kidding me.
那是我们现在为什么需要了解 你加入还是不加入?
That's why we need to know right now, are you in or out?
加入
In.
好
Good.
我们都已经审查通过这项证据 所以 看你的吧
We've already been through the evidence, so just take your time.
你是说盖塔看过这个名单 并且没有做任何事情?
You're telling me that Gaeta saw this list and didn't do a damned thing about it?
当他看到这个名单的时候
We have no idea of knowing what
我们不知道盖塔做了什么或是没有做什么
Gaeta did or did not do when he saw the list.
我的天  整件事就像一个噩梦
My Gods, the whole thing's like a bad dream,
只是我们都醒来了  可叛国贼还在那儿
only we woke up and the traitors are all still here.
有罪
Guilty.
现在的有罪判断是五比零
The vote's five to none in favor of guilty.
这是没有异议的
It's got to be unanimous.
军士长 你是最后一个评判的
Chief, you're the last to vote.
离开这里  山姆
Get out of here, Sam.
我想和我老婆说句话 我要现在说
I'd like to talk to my wife. I'd like to do it now.
你已经评判过了  休息一下吧
We already have your vote. Take a break.
听着  我退出是因为我不想继续杀人
Hey, I quit because I'm not looking for ways to keep killing people.
但我需要  山姆
Well, I need this, Sam.
又能怎么样呢?
So what?
把人们从减压舱中丢出去
Throwing a few people out of airlock
能让你感觉好受吗?
is gonna make you feel better about yourself?
请相信我  他们不是那些该被锁进减压舱的人
Because, believe me, those aren't the people that kept you locked in that room.
就是他们 并且不只是为了我
They'll do. And not just for me,
是为了所有留在那颗星球上的人
but for every person we left back on that planet,
因为必须有人要为此付出代价
because someone has got to pay.
你可以与我们一起干  或是别管我们
So you can either get with it or you can get lost.
那是你想要得吗  卡拉?  你想让我离开?
Is that what you want, Kara? You want me to leave?
山姆不想说他有罪
He doesn't want to say he's guilty,
是因为盖塔是一个不错的人 对吗  军士长?
because Gaeta is such a good guy. Right, Chief?
所有人都喜欢盖塔 那么就让他不要再被迷惑
Everyone likes Gaeta, so let's let him off the hook.
那让我们从其他方面看看这个人吧
Let's just look the other way on this one.
嗯  很多好人都为他们所做的付出了代价
Well, a lot of good people had to pay the price for what they did,
他们在新卡布里卡所做的决定 就像我的老婆
the choices they made on New Caprica. Like my wife.
那是对的 艾伦通了敌
That's right, Ellen collaborated.
把地下抵抗组织的信息透露给了赛昂人 她付出了生命的代价
Gave the Cylons information on the Resistance and she died for it.
因为那是叛国通敌的代价
Because that's the price of collaborating with the enemy.
相比盖塔  我更喜欢她
And I liked her a lot more than I like Gaeta.
听着  山姆
Look, Sam,
我现在处在不同的立场
I'm in a different place now.
我不知道该如何向你解释
I don't know how else to explain it to you,
但当我走出监狱
but I got out of that cell,
那就像有人把世界染了另一种颜色
and it's like someone painted the world in different colors.
我现在看着你
And I look at you,
我都想把你的眼睛挖出来  只因为它在看着我
and I want to tear your eyes out just for looking at me.
我只想狠扁一个人  而那人最好是你
I just want to hurt someone and it might as well be you.
所以你该在那发生之前滚开
So you should probably go before that happens.
波塔尔签署的处决命令  组织行刑队
Baltar signed death warrants, organized murder squads.
是他从一开始就通敌叛国的
He collaborated with the enemy from day one.
是波塔尔  不是盖塔
Baltar, not Gaeta.
都是些同样可憎的东西
It's the same gods-damned thing!
他是对的
SEELIX: He's right.
很多人因他们而死的  军士长
A lot of people died because of them, Chief.
好吧  有罪
Fine. Guilty.
还记得这个吗?
Remember this?
我不想再要它了
I don't want this anymore.
山姆
Sam.
带走他
SEELIX: Take him!
转过头来! 跪下! 跪下!
Turn around. On your knees. On your knees!
菲里克斯・盖塔
Felix Gaeta,
你已经被特别法庭审判并判决
you've been tried and found guilty of crimes against humanity
有反人类罪
by a circle of your peers
这是由联邦总统授权的特别法庭
as duly authorized by the President of the Colonies.
如果你有什么想要申辩的 就是现在了
If you have any words to offer in your own defense, now is the time.
拜托  菲里克斯  说啊 我们会听
Come on, Felix, talk. We'll listen.
没错  就是那样
Yeah, that's right.
我们会听你说  你是如何隐藏在波塔尔身边
We'll listen to you tell us how hiding behind Baltar's skirt
那其实是你帮助反抗组织的办法
was actually your way of helping the insurgency.
快说
Say something.
说什么呢?
What's the point?
我已经尝试解释了
I already tried to explain it.
我不会乞求的
I'm not gonna beg.
太糟了  你四个月来都没有长进
Too bad you didn't grow that spine four months ago.
乞求
Beg.
乞求!
乞求!        瑟瑞丝…
Beg! TIGH: Thrace...
不!      乞求
No. Beg.
拜托  菲里克斯  告诉他们  在整段时间里
Come on, Felix, tell them how you were actually working
你是如何为抵抗组织工作的
for the Resistance the entire time!
说啊!
Come on!
告诉他们所有重要的信息是你传出来的
Tell them all about the important information that you were giving up.
告诉他们所有的信息和那个狗食盆
Tell them about all the messages, and the dog bowl and everything else.
还有其他的         什么?
Just tell me. What?
她说了什么?   她刚才说了什么?
What did she say? What did she just say?
一边儿去
Back up!
她刚才说了什么?  你跟她说了什么?
What did she just say? What did you say to her?
告诉我  你跟她说了什么?
Tell me, what did you say to her?
那是一个黄色的狗食盆
It was a yellow dog bowl.
那是一个信号 那代表着在垃圾堆的抽屉里有情报
It was a signal. It meant there was a message in the garbage dump.
是我转交的情报.那是一个信号
Turn it over, it was a signal.
意味着在垃圾堆的抽屉里有一个情报
It meant there was a message at the garbage dump.
噢  原来是你啊
Oh, that was you.
噢  我的天
Oh, my God...
你在干什么?  军士长
What are you doing? Chief...
那儿是有一个黄色的狗食盆 是我用到的
There was a yellow dog bowl. I used it.
你还问过谁会是情报源的呢  上校
But I never knew who the source was, Colonel.
他不可能从别处知道的
There's no other way he could have known.
只有他才有可能接触到那些信息
He's the only other one that would know about it.
就是他告诉我们处决名单
He's the reason we know about the death lists,
他是我能救得了凯莉的原因 他是我们现在在船上的原因
he's the reason I saved Cally, he's the reason we're on this ship.
就是他告诉我们内线消息的
He's the one who gave us the inside information.
他是我们的内线  上校
There's our source, Colonel.
我做了我能做到的
I did what I could.
我不知道我还能做些什么
I don't know what else I could've done.
这是什么该死的东西?
What the hell is this?
这是完全合法的
It's all perfectly legal.
你会在档案中找到总统的行政命令 授权一个…
You'll find a signed executive order on file authorizing a secret jury
由6人组成的秘密法庭  去调查  审判  和执行在
of six men and women to try, sentence and execute people guilty
战争期间有叛国通敌罪的人
of extraordinary crimes while collaborating with the enemy at a time of war.
同样有我签了名的死刑执行书
There's also a death warrant with my signature for every conviction.
你做总统真是个闹剧 从现在开始被终止了
Your presidency is a farce. It stops right now.
如果他们有罪  他们被相应的法庭审判
If they're guilty, they'll be tried by a jury of their peers.
他们有一个法庭 但他们没有律师
They have a jury, but they don't get lawyers.
他们不需要几周或者几个月去搞那个审判
They don't get to showboat for weeks and months on end.
他们也不会责备"体制的问题"
They don't get to blame the system.
并且他们也不会被当作烈士或是什么无辜的人
And they don't get lasting fame as martyrs or innocent people
只是在一个错误的地点和错误的时间
just in the wrong place at the wrong time.
让他们就此消失  就是现在!
They just disappear, now,
在占领与新时代来临之间的
in the gray twilight between the long night of the occupation
漫长黑夜中的灰暗拂晓
and the dawn of a new era.
你可以走进一个干净的办公室 手上不用沾上他们的血
You come into office clean, without their blood on your hands.
很好  谢谢你  真像是诗歌一般
Well, thank you, that's very poetic.
但是你有个问题   总统先生
However, you have a problem, Mr. President.
法律赋予所有人在审判的时要有辩护律师
Everyone, by law, is entitled to a trial with representation. Everyone.
这是不能因总统的一时兴起就被违背的
It is not an option to be discarded at the President's whim.
你以为公开审判你就能够获得正义?
You think by making the trials public that you'll find justice?
是  我就这样想.
Yes, I do.
算了吧 劳拉 你不会那么天真吧
Come on, Laura. You're not that naive.
我告诉你如果把这些案子交给法庭会发生什么
Let me tell you what's going to happen if these cases go to trial.
那会让舰队浪费数月  甚至可能几年
It'll consume this fleet for months, maybe years.
人们会排队去作证告发他们的邻居
People will be lining up to testify against their neighbors.
这会像是马戏团…
It'll be a circus.
给乌合之众的表演
An entertainment for the mob
并且你会每年都签署死刑命令书
and you'll be signing death warrants almost every day.
那会是你下个任期想做的吗  劳拉?
Is that how you want to spend your next term, Laura,
做一个刽子手的头?
as executioner-in-chief?
"以我的生命"
PRIEST:... with every fiber of my being.
"... with every fiber of my being. "
祝贺你  总统女士
Congratulations, Madam President.
谢谢你
Thank you.
感谢大家再次信任我
Thank you all for once again entrusting me
从事此项高层行政工作
with this high office of civil service.
今天对我们来说是一个新的开始
Today is a new beginning for all of us.
我们同担共同的命运
We share a unique destiny,
我们要创造自己的未来 但我们也不该遗忘过去
but our future is ours to shape and our past cannot be forgotten.
新的一天需要新的想法
A new day requires new thinking.
同时我想值此机会
And while I had intended on using this occasion
向大家公布一个一个关于检举办公室调查的
as an opportunity to announce the formation of a special prosecutor's office
叛国通敌法案
charged with investigating acts of collaboration with the enemy,
我决定以不同的方式来替换它
I have decided instead that a different gesture is called for on this,
在我新任期的头一天 以总统的名义
the first day of my next term as your president.
我们都需要正义
We all feel the need for justice,
我们都想要报仇
and we all feel the need for vengeance,
把这两者区分 在现在是很难的
and telling the difference between the two can be difficult at times.
我们都是赛昂人的受害者 并且没有人能做到公正不阿
We are all victims of the Cylons and none of us can be impartial.
我确实不能
I certainly can't.
所以  今天我成立一个真相委员会
So today, I am forming a commission on truth and reconciliation,
完整地来听大家的故事 并记录流传给子孙后代
to hear our stories and record them for posterity.
这不存在任何的起诉
There will be no prosecutions.
我已经在这个舰队中向所有的人类 签发了大赦法案
I am issuing a general pardon for every human being in this fleet.
这在今天可能不会受到欢迎
This will not be a popular move today.
但是我相信这是唯一的方法
But I truly believe that this is the only way for us to move forward in strength
让大家在和解与恢复的精神下  奋力前行
in a spirit of healing and reconciliation.
我要谢谢大家不断的耐心和勇气
I thank you for your continued patience and courage.
日安!
Good day.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗨 军士长 要坐吗
Hey, Chief, want a seat?